appvirality.com 2019-04-23

# Privacy Policy

### **Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally Identifiable Information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as described in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time. Rest assured, we will notify you of any material changes which you can review as the updated Privacy Policy posted on the AppVirality website. If you do not accept the updated Privacy Policy, you may terminate Service as provided in the AppVirality Service Agreement; otherwise the updated Privacy Policy will apply to you.

**What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our blog, website or app?**

We collect certain personal information from Customers when a Customer signs up to our Service that can be used to identify you, such as your name, e-mail address, company name and any other information that we deem relevant for the purpose of providing you with our Service or which you provided to us voluntarily. The information we collect from you, to the extent that it is private, is disclosed only in accordance with our Terms of Service and/or this Privacy Policy.

As you navigate the Service, we may also collect information through the use of commonly-used information-gathering tools, such as cookies and web beacons (“Web Site Navigational Information”). Web Site Navigational Information includes standard information from your Web browser (such as browser type and browser language), your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, and the actions you take on the Service (such as the web pages viewed and the links clicked).

Through our import process, we may also collect information provided by Customers, such as the name, company name, email address etc of Customer End Users that you choose to share with us. When you provide us with personal information about your Customer End Users, we will only use this information for the specific reason for which it is provided, such as to add new records to your account, or as agreed in the applicable agreement with Customer.

We collect certain payment and billing information when you register for our paid Services. For example, we ask you to designate a billing representative, including name and contact information, upon registration. You might also provide payment information, such as payment card details, which we collect via secure payment processing services.

**Non-Identifying Information**

Whenever you visit our Site, we may collect non-identifying information from you, such as your referring URL, browser, operating system, cookie information, and Internet Service Provider. Without a subpoena, voluntary compliance on the part of your Internet Service Provider, or additional records from a third-party, this information alone cannot usually be used to identify you.

**How do we use your information?**

We use personal information you provide to us and information that we automatically collect to provide you with better user experience, troubleshoot problems, resolve technical issues, bill any amounts due from you, resolve billing disputes, send you in-app messages,onboarding emails, personalized and customized marketing materials and promotional offers, as well as to protect us against fraud and other criminal activities.

You will be receiving emails about your account status and payment information such as information as to when your trial will end and if recent payment has failed or succeeded. 

We may also use your information to analyze our marketing efforts and product usage, as well as to improve the AppVirality website and application and tailor it to your needs to provide you with a better user experience.

We use Stripe, a payment processor which helps us collect and store payment details which we are using to bill any amounts that are due from you.

**How do we protect your information?**

We do not use vulnerability scanning and/or scanning to PCI standards. We do not use Malware Scanning. We do use an SSL certificate. We only provide articles and information.

**Do we use ‘cookies’?**

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the sites’ or service providers’ systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

AppVirality occasionally uses the AdRoll display advertising network to collect visitor data on our site and then serve targeted display ads to you on other sites. Our partners use technology such as cookies and web beacons to collect this data. For more information or to opt-out of this type of advertising, please visit AdRoll’s privacy policy.

**We use cookies to:**

Keep track of advertisements. You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You can do this through your browser settings. Since each browser is a little different, look at your browser’s Help Menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you turn cookies off, some features will be disabled. It won’t affect the site user experience.

**Phishing**

AppVirality doesn’t treat ‘phishing’ or identity theft lightly. Safeguarding information to help protect you from identity theft is a top priority. We do not and will not, at any time, request your credit card information, your account ID, login password, or national identification numbers in a non-secure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication.

**Information sharing/disclosure**

We may share aggregated information about Registration Data that **does not** include personally identifiable information and we may otherwise disclose non-identifying Information with third parties for industry analysis, demographic profiling and other purposes. Any aggregated information shared in these contexts **Otherwise, we will never share any customer data, aggregated or not, unless required to by law**.

We may employ third-party companies and individuals to facilitate our site and service, to provide the service on our behalf, to perform site-related services (e.g., without limitation, maintenance services, database management, web analytics and improvement of the site’s features) or to assist us in analyzing how our site and service are used. These third parties may have access to your registration data or customer data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

We will obtain assurances from our third party partners that **they will safeguard personal information** consistent with the policies set forth in this Privacy Policy. Examples of appropriate assurances that may be provided by third party partners include a contract obligating the third party partner to provide at least the same level of protection for the personal information it has access to as is required by the Privacy Shield Principles. **If we become aware that a third party partner is using or disclosing personal information in violation of this Privacy Policy, we will take reasonable steps to prevent or stop the use or disclosure**.

**Business Transfers**

In the case of a merger, acquisition or reorganization, AppVirality may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of its assets, including your customer data, in order to provide you continued service.

**Google**

Google’s advertising requirements can be summed up by Google’s **[Advertising Principles](https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en)**. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users.

**We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website**

Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt-out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy.

We have implemented the following:

**Remarketing with Google AdSense**

We, along with third-party vendors such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.

**Opting out:**

Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative Opt Out page or by using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add-on.

**Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement**

We cooperate with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We will only disclose information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (including but not limited to subpoenas), to protect the property and rights of AppVirality, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, any illegal, unethical or legally actionable activity. We respect the ownership rights of AppVirality Customers in Customer Data and, accordingly, AppVirality will exercise commercially reasonable efforts to inform you of any request made to us for disclosure of your Customer Data and to cooperate with you in taking those measures permitted by law for limiting disclosure of your Customer Data.

**California Online Privacy Protection Act**

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require any person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting Personally Identifiable Information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals or companies with whom it is being shared.

**According to CalOPPA, we agree to the following:**

Users can visit our site anonymously.

Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our homepage or at a minimum, on the first significant page after entering our website.

Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’ and can easily be found on the page specified above.

You will be notified of any Privacy Policy changes.

On our Privacy Policy Page you can change your personal information by emailing us.

**How does our site handle Do Not Track signals?**

We honor Do Not Track signals and Do Not Track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

**Does our site allow third-party behavioral tracking?**

It’s also important to note that we do not allow third-party behavioral tracking.

**COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)**

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under the age of 13 years old, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, United States’ consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under the age of 13 years old.

**Fair Information Practices**

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

**Fair Information Practices**

In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:

We will notify you via email within 7 business days.

We also agree to the Individual Redress Principle which requires that individuals have the right to legally pursue enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

**CAN SPAM Act**

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

**We collect your email address in order to:**

Send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.

We will only use personal information for the purpose for which it was collected or subsequently authorized by the individual.

We will take reasonable steps to ensure that personal information is relevant to its intended use, complete, and current.

**To be in accordance with CANSPAM, we agree to the following:**

Not use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.

Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way.

Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters.

Monitor third-party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.

Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.

Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.

**Enforcement and Liability**

AppVirality will conduct compliance audits of its privacy practices to verify adherence to this Privacy Policy. AppVirality employees that are found to have violated this Privacy Policy will be subjected to disciplinary action up to and including termination of their employment with AppVirality.

**If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can email us at**

privacy@appvirality.com and we will promptly remove you from **ALL** correspondence.

You may review, update, correct or delete your registration data and customer data, including the personally identifiable information in your registration profile by contacting us. If you completely delete all such information, then your account may become deactivated.

**Contacting Us**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy, you may contact us using the information below.

Mail us at privacy@appvirality.com

Effective from 25th May, 2018
